Hello and welcome to the sixth tutorial
on how to program in Gcript 2. Let's
open our MPC in our level
editor. And you can see I changed a bit
of the code, but not really by a
lot. It says as soon as the player says
something, it will run this. Now, let's
do talk about variables. Variables are
like boxes. Boxes that do things. Okay,
let's name make our own variable now.
Bob is equal to one semicolon. What we
just did is we created a variable called
Bob and we made it equal to one. It's
sort of like in
algebra when you make x= to 1 or x= to 5
or y equal to whatever. It's essentially
like that except where you can name the
variable anything you want. Well, the
same algebra, but you know, now let's do
this. This chat is equal to Bob. We're
making it it's chat equal to Bob. If you
add semicolon, I
mean not semicolon, quotes, then it's
going to say Bob. But if we take out the
quotes, it's going to say what's in Bob.
So, it's going to say one. So, let's
test
that. We say hi. It says one.
Now
let's do something else. Let's make it
if. If statements are like functions
sort of except they check what if
whatever is equal in these parenthesis
is true. It's going to run these quotes
then just continue on and do whatever
else. Let's do this. If Bob is equal to
one, you have to add two equal signs
because you're checking to see if it's
equal to one. You're not making equal.
If Bob is equal to one, then make it say
this. Equals Bob is
one
there. Save it and run. Hi, Bob is one.
We can also make it do if Bob is less
than or equal to, it's greater than or
equal to. if it's not equal to one or
you can just do less than or greater
than. There's a lot of different
commands you can do, but those are like
the most basic ones.
Now, let's
say Bob is equal to
two. Well, then what
happens? We save and
upload. Nothing happens cuz it checks to
see if this is true, but it's not. So it
completely skips everything in the
brackets and goes onto here which is
nothing. But let's say we want to do if
it's not equal to one, we want to do
something else. For that we would do
else like this. If Bob is not equal to
one, which it currently isn't, it's
going to run whatever is in here. Pass
the else in the brackets. But this chat
is equal to Bob is not one.
semicolon. We save
it and upload. Say, "Hi, Bob is not
one." Well, anyway, that concludes this
tutorial. You learned about a little bit
about if statements. You learned
about variables a bit. We'll learn about
more later. So anyway, bye.